hello everyone my name is Greg and I Dev
stuff welcome to episode 31 of the
tactics game in unity so in the last
episode we have made it so you can Place
characters in The placeable positions
when you set up the scenes before the
battle but right now we're using find
object of type to communicate to the
unit placement manager instead we will
use scriptable object to pass the
information to the unit placement
manager instead we will use scriptable
object to communicate between combat
stage placement notes and the manager we
will use scriptable object as a
container for information to pass to the
manager
let's hide public views which we are not
assigning in the editor
so we need to create a scriptable object
called placement node list
set it to be scriptable object
add create asset menu attribute so you
will be able to create instances of the
placement node list in the editor create
a list of nodes
then make a clear method which will
clear the list of all nodes in the list
and make a method to add nodes into the
list
good
so instead of adding replaceable unit
node directly to the manager we will be
adding this node to the list instead by
creating field for the node list
and calling add on start making the
notes self-report into the list
so now inside unit placement manager
instead of storing the nodes we will use
the nodes list
create the field for the placement node
list
and we need to clear this list when we
begin placing our units
we will be using list of nodes from the
scriptable object
and when we are done placing our units
we want to clear placement node list
which can be done when we unload unit
placement manager out of our memory so
inside on Destroy cold placement node
list.clear good
create and reference the list of nodes
this is it
this just should work now
I'm sorry for a very long absence of
this series I
hit an let's say mental block on the on
this series my apologies good this is it
for this episode if you have any
questions or any ideas about code please
leave your comment below if you want to
support me further you can find links to
my patreon in the description with best
regards see in the next episode